[Music] Hi! Wow... Oh my god.
[音乐]嗨！ 哇，天哪
This is quite amazing.
这真是太神奇了
I'm really excited to be here at this conference.
我很高兴能参加这次会议
I'm so excited to be talking to all of you, who apparently are developers?
很高兴能与大家交流， 谁是开发者？
That's what it says back there on the screen.
这就是屏​​幕上显示的内容
I assume it's true.
我认为这是真的很棒
How many people in this room have used open-source software?
这个房间有几个人使用过开源软件？
[Audience raises hands] Trick question!
[观众举手]这是个逗趣问题！
I'm just trying to get you to warm up with some morning exercise.
我只是想让你做些热身运动
Everybody raises their hand.
每个人都举起手来
Okay, great.
好，太棒了
Let me ask you a simpler question.
让我问一个更简单的问题
How many of you use open-source software because 'it doesn't cost anything'?
你们中有多少人使用开源软件是因为“它不需要任何成本”？
How many of you use it because it gives you freedom?
有多少人使用它是因为它给您带来自由？
Okay, now we're getting at it.
好的，现在我们要正式开始了
Many of you probably work with open-source software.
你们很多人可能都使用开源软件工作
Many of you probably work with collaborative programming and open systems.
你们中的许多人可能使用协作编程和开放系统软件
You work on open applications, programming interfaces.
您在开源的应用以及编程接口的基础上工作
You work with open libraries.
您使用开放的库
You work with patent-free software and technologies, with open protocols and open interfaces.
您使用的是无专利的软件和技术， 它们是开放的协议和开放的接口
None of that is because of how much it costs.
我们使用它们不是因为少花多少钱
It's because it gives you freedom.
这是因为它给您自由
I think that's one of the main things that people outside our industry do not understand.
我认为这是我们行业外的人不理解的主要事情之一
But if you're as old as me, you probably remember that it wasn't always like that.
但是如果你和我一样大，你可能还记得事情 并非总是那样
Throughout the '80s and '90s, there was a big battle over the future of software; whether
在整个80年代和90年代， 围绕软件的未来有一场大战；关于未来的软件行业是否
proprietary software would dominate, whether open software would be available to everyone
将占据主导地位的专有软件 或者向所有人开放的开放软件
and used by everyone.
并被所有人使用
I remember a time when I had to persuade companies that an open-source version...
我记得有一段时间我不得不说服公司，那些开源软件...
the Unix operating system was not only as good, but probably better,
Unix操作系统不仅同样棒，而且可能更棒
than the closed-source Sun Microsystems operating system that they used.
比他们使用的闭源操作系统Sun Microsystems更棒
I had to persuade them that they could use these systems to replace their proprietary
我不得不说服他们，说服他们用这些开源系统取代他们专有的
servers, file servers, network servers, firewalls, routers, etc.
服务器，文件服务器，网络服务器，防火墙，路由器等
There was a time when Bill Gates from Microsoft said that the internet would be one component
曾经有一段时间，微软的比尔·盖茨（Bill Gates）说互联网将是....的一个组成部分
of the information super-highway.
信息高速公路
Just one component.
只是一个组件而已
Because what was more interesting, was how data would be used in proprietary fashion
因为更有趣的是数据将以专有方式使用
and propagated over proprietary protocols and closed systems.
并通过专有协议和封闭系统传播
The idea was that corporations wouldn't open to the internet, because it was "too messy,"
公司不会向互联网开放，因为它“太乱了”
"too weird," and had too much porn.
“太奇怪了”，并且充斥了色情内容
Instead, corporate systems would be perfect closed gardens.
相反，公司系统将是完美的封闭式花园
Secure with quality, curated content that was protected from the wide world.
通过优质，精心策划的措施来确保安全; 保护免受广阔世界的侵害
If you worked in a company that actually tried to put that into practice, you discovered
如果您在一家公司工作，你会发现这家公司实际上想把这一点付诸实践---
that those systems ended up being insecure, virus-infested wastelands of stale, useless content.
这些系统最终是不安全的， 病毒感染的荒地，内容陈旧，毫无用处
Eventually, most of the people who worked in these companies had a second phone
最终，大多数在这些公司中工作的人都买了第二部手机
(maybe a smartphone) so they could look up things on the internet.
（也许是智能手机），这样他们就可以 在互联网上查找信息
The internet won.
互联网赢了
The open, uncontrolled, unrestrained internet won.
开放，不受控制，不受限制的互联网赢了
But it wasn't obvious that it was going to win.
但真正的赢家并不明显
TCP/IP won.
TCP / IP赢了
There was a time when people said ridiculous things like "I'm not so interested in the Web."
曾经有人说过一些荒谬的观点，诸如“我对网络不太感兴趣”
"I'm interested in the technology behind the Web: HTML."
“我对这项技术背后的技术很感兴趣：比如WEB:HTML。”
[Laughter] To misunderstand the power and purpose of a system like the Web so much,
[笑声]这其实误解了像网络这样的系统的力量和目的
as to think that the value of that comes from a representational format for data,
这种观点认为它的价值来自数据的表示形式
and the ability to link it to other data.
以及将其链接到其他数据的能力
And miss the point that the really interesting thing is the ability of anyone, anywhere, to become a publisher.
这忽略了一点，真正有趣的事情是： 任何地方，任何人成为发布者的能力
The democratisation of publishing.
自由发声的权利民主化
The open access to all of the information in the world, where if it is closed then it is irrelevant.
能自由的获取世界上所有的信息； 如果它是封闭的，那就无关紧要了
If it is not accessible, it is irrelevant.
如果无法访问，那么它就是不想关的
Today, people say, "I'm not interested in Bitcoin.
今天，人们说：“我对比特币不感兴趣。“
I'm interested in the technology behind Bitcoin: the blockchain."
我对比特币背后的技术感兴趣：区块链。”
Two days ago when this conference opened, people were asked 'what is the thing you're most interested in?'
两天前的会议开幕时，人们被提问“您最感兴趣的是什么？”
"Blockchain" was right in the middle of the screen, the biggest word there.
“区块链”就在中间，是屏幕上最大的字
Blockchain.
Blockchain
The blockchain is a data structure.
区块链是一种数据结构
It's not even a particularly interesting data structure. It is a hashed linked list.
它甚至不是一个特别有趣的数据结构。 这是一个哈希链接列表
From a technical perspective, it's kind of boring.
从技术角度来看，有点无聊
What's really interesting about the blockchain is how the blockchain is created.
区块链技术真正有趣的部分是： 它是如何产生的
What is the process for recording data in a blockchain?
在区块链中记录数据的过程是什么？
Bitcoin introduced a mechanism to do that which is open, decentralised, neutral, borderless,
比特币引入了一种机制来做到这一点: 开放，分散，中立，无国界，
and censorship resistant -- kind of like the Web.
且不受审查限制-有点像网络
That's really the interesting thing about the open Web: that it is open,
这个开放的web真的很有趣：它是开放的，
that no one really controls all of it, and even when some companies control big parts of it,
没有人真正控制所有这些，甚至当一些公司控制其中的大部分时，
there are still parts that are free, weird, encrypted, underground.
仍然有部分是免费的， 看起来很奇怪，加密的，地下生存
Still open to creating incredible new inventions like Bitcoin.
仍然对创造像比特币这样不可思议的新发明持开放态度
It popped out of the internet and no one expected it.
它突然出现在互联网之外，没人能预料到
Neutral.
它是中立的
For the most part, content is routed across the Web without regard to the content itself,
在大多数情况下，内容会跨过web， web是不会考虑内容本身的网络，
or really to the source and destination.
以及真正的来源和目的地
Censorship-resistant.
它是抗审查的
You cannot erase the Web, you cannot (easily) remove information from the Web.
您无法擦除网络，也无法 （轻松）从Web上删除信息
Bitcoin introduced a way to apply this to trusted information, specifically the most
比特币引入了一种将其应用于可信信息的方法，尤其是最需要信任的信息
important and trusted information, which is the ownership of currency.
最重要且需要信赖的信息：就是货币的所有权
Money.
钱
It created a way to have a recording of ownership in the blockchain without allowing anyone
它创造了一种在区块链中记录所有权的方式，不接受任何人的控制
to have control over who can own money, how they can spend it, or who can record on this blockchain.
控制谁可以拥有货币，谁可以花费货币，或者谁可以在这个区块链上记录
Bitcoin made money open, neutral, borderless, censorship-resistant, and decentralised.
比特币创造的货币开放，中立，无国界， 抗审查性，且去中心化
The artefact of that technology, the deliverable, the product,
这项技术的人工制品， 最终的交付成果，
the thing that gets recorded on your software node, is the blockchain.
在您的软件节点记录下来的东西是区块链
That blockchain is a necessary but not sufficient component to create the real magic,
区块链是创造神奇魔法的必要但不充分条件
which is a platform for trust that is not controlled by anyone, that cannot be erased or changed
这是个不受任何人控制、 任何人都无法删除或更改的信任平台
after it has been recorded.
在它被记录下来之后
A system that is open, neutral, borderless, and censorship-resistant.
一个开放，中立，无国界，和抗审查的系统
It's not about the blockchain.
这与区块链无关
In fact, if you take the blockchain technology, and you apply it in an environment that is closed,
实际上，如果您采用区块链技术， 然后将其应用在封闭的环境中
controlled by one party that can decide which transactions get recorded and which ones do not...
由一方控制，可以决定记录哪些交易，不记录哪些交易...
[There are] "good" transactions and "bad" transactions, "evil" transactions, ones that should be censored.
[有]“好”交易和“坏”交易， 对于那些“邪恶”交易应予以审查。
Then you lose all of the interesting properties of the open blockchain.
然后，您将失去所有开放式区块链有趣的属性
Whenever I talk about this space, I always put at least one word before "blockchain,"
每当我谈论这个领域时，我总是在“区块链”之前至少放一个词，
and that is 'open.'
那是“开放的”
'Open' means open-source, open-access, open to innovation without permission.
“开放”是指开源，开放获取，不需要授权就可以进行创新
It means innovation at the edge, not the center.
这意味着创新处于周边，而不是中心
It means no one is in control.
这意味着没有人可以控制
It means there is no censorship.
这意味着没有审查制度
It means it is neutral.
这意味着它是中立的
You don't require any patent to participate in this technology.
您不需要任何专利即可参与在这项技术中
It is neutral because in this system of trust, the source, destination, content,
这是中立的，因为在这种信任系统中， 来源，目的地，内容，
and even purpose of your transaction does not matter.
甚至交易目的也没有关系
It will be routed and there is no way to stop someone from routing.
它将被路由并且无法停止 没有办法能阻止它被路由
Almost every day, I meet people who come to me and say, "I'm kind of interested in Bitcoin,
几乎每天我都会遇到一些人说：“我对比特币很感兴趣，
but I'm more interested in all the other applications we can do with the blockchain."
但我对使用区块链的所有其他应用程序更感兴趣。”
Not even "the blockchain," just "blockchain."
甚至没有说“使用区块链的程序”， 只有“区块链”
It's become a generic, abstract word.
它已成为一个通用的抽象词
In most cases, that word is meaningless.
在大多数情况下，该词是没有意义的
What it means to them is "I'm trying to do everything where I previously used a database,
对他们来说这其实意味着: “我正在努力用它来替代我之前使用的数据库，
only now we can do it with something that is a hundred-thousand times slower and less well-tested."
区别在于，我们是在用一种速度慢了十万倍，而且测试还不够完善的东西来替换。”
If you create a centralised blockchain, if you have a central point of control;
如果创建集中式区块链 您有一个中心控制点；
if it's not open, borderless, censorship-resistant, and neutral, then you should have used
如果它不是开放的，无边界的，不受审查的，和中立的，那么你应该使用
Microsoft SQL Server Enterprise Edition or Oracle.
Microsoft SQL Server企业版或Oracle
The problem is, no one is going to pay a consultant to re-build Dubai's real-estate records on Microsoft SQL.
问题是，没有人会花钱请顾问用Microsoft SQL重建迪拜的房地产记录
That's not going to get you any magic venture capital money sprinkled over you.
那不会给你带来任何炒作，不会带来风险投资
[That only happens] when you go to Silicon Valley, go in front of the bathroom mirror in your hotel room,
[这只会发生]当您去硅谷时， 在酒店房间浴室镜子的前面，
turn off the light and say "blockchain, blockchain, blockchain" three times.
关掉灯，说“区块链，区块链，区块链”三遍
A venture capitalist [will] jump out of the bathtub and start throwing money at you!
风险资本家[将]跳出浴缸，然后开始向您扔钱！
[Laughter]
[笑声]
I did a talk which was censored on Facebook the first day it was published.
我做了一个演讲，在Facebook发表的第一天就被审查了
It was called "Blockchain versus Bullshit."
它被称为“区块链与扯淡”
Apparently that word "bullshit" is not good for Facebook and censorship is something they do,
显然“ bullshit”一词对Facebook不利， 因为他们立马把这个演讲办掉了
which kind of proves the point [about centralised blockchains] really.
这在某种程度上证明了集中化区块链的重要性
It's about decentralisation, censorship resistance, open-access.
它是关于权力下放，抗审查制度，开放获取的
It's about the ability to use a 'bad' word to make an important point, to use the shock value
它是关于使用一个反对字眼来表达一个重要观点的能力
to get people's attention and [hope they] listen to the rest of the message.
引起人们的关注并[希望他们] 听听下面的话
But that's okay, because I don't use Facebook anyway!
但这没关系，因为我根本不用Facebook！
The bottom line is that this technology is interesting because, for the first time in
最重要的是，这项技术有趣的地方是， 这是历史上第一次
history, it takes one of humanity's oldest technology (money) and one of the most important
它使人类最古老的技术之一（货币）， 这也是历史上最重要的一项技术--
aspects of human behaviour (trust), and embeds these in an open, inter-operable network protocol
关于人类（信任）行为的各个方面， 嵌入到开放的，可互操作的网络协议
without central control.
没有中央控制
This has never happened before.
这种情况在历史上从未发生过
Yes, you could imagine a myriad of applications where the ability to trust in the network protocol
是的，您可以想象有无数的应用程序， 这些程序信任网络协议的能力
and not have to trust in the other party you're interacting with, without a third-party
而不必信任对方 ， 您在没有第三方的情况下进行交互
that acts as an intermediary.
这种技术充当了媒介的角色
You can imagine many different applications.
您可以想象许多不同的应用程序
The problem is that a lot of those applications really depend on first establishing...
问题是很多这样的应用程序都依赖于首先建立...
the first fundamental application: value as a content type.
第一个基本应用：其内容是价值
When you turn money into a content type, make it something that is routable across the internet
当您将货币变成一种信息时， 它可以通过互联网路由
from any point to any other point, without reference to any third party, self-verifiable, self-authorising,
从任何点到任何其他点，不涉及任何第三方，可自我验证，自我授权，
Independently routable money as a network protocol.
作为网络协议的可独立路由的货币
That creates the basis for all of the other applications.
这个应用为所有其他方面奠定了基础
That creates the basis for applications of security and trust that we need to build as
这为我们需要构建的安全和信任的应用奠定了基础
an infrastructure to start everything else.
这是开始其他一切的基础架构
If the blockchain is open, decentralised, neutral, and censorship-resistant,
如果区块链是开放的，去中心化的，中立且不受审查的影响
then it can be used for so many other interesting applications.
那么它可以用于很多其他有趣的应用程序
But most of the companies you work for will not use it that way.
但是您工作的大多数公司不会那样用
They see the internet of money and they want to build an intranet.
他们看到了货币的互联网 他们想建立一个局域网
The natural motivation of a corporation is control.
公司的自然动机是控制
The natural motivation of a government is control.
政府的自然动机是控制
They see this open system and they say, "We kind of like it. Immutability, recordability...
他们看到了这个开放系统，然后说， “我们有点喜欢。它的不变性，可记录性...
Auditability, forensic analysis, cryptography... all of these cute things.
可审核性，法医分析，密码学... 所有这些都是不错的东西
Can we have them without the open, borderless, neutral, censorship-resistant aspects of it?
我们可以没有开放，无边界，中立，抗审查的特性吗？
We would like to make it closed, controlled, censurable, and profitable (for us)."
我们想使其封闭，受控，（对我们而言）是可审查的和有利可图的。”
They will build great intranets of money and they will be stale wastelands just like the
他们将建立巨大的货币局域网 他们将成为陈腐的不毛之地
Microsoft FrontPage / Outlook shit you have in the back office of your corporation.
Microsoft FrontPage / Outlook是您公司后台的垃圾
[Applause]
[掌声]
When somebody says, "I'm going to apply the blockchain to my new application,"
当有人说：“我要申请将区块链技术应用到我的新程序里面，”
the first question you should ask is, "What kind of blockchain? Why do you need one?"
您应该问的第一个问题是，“什么样的区块链？为什么需要一个？”
I only have one slide, but if I wanted to do a perfect presentation about blockchains
我只有一张幻灯片，但是如果我想做一个关于区块链的完美展示
to a corporate environment, as one of my friends on Twitter recently said: "You only need one slide...
对于企业环境，我的一个Twitter上的好友最近说：“您只需要一张幻灯片...
It says 'you don't need a blockchain.' Thank you! Questions?" [Laughter]
那就是：“您不需要区块链。” 谢谢！有问题吗？” [笑声]
The bottom line is that the number of applications where you truly need a borderless, global,
真相是，您真正需要的，是一个无国界，全球化的...
censorship-resistant, neutral platform to establish a level of trust and immutability
不受审查的，信任和不可改变的平台
that cannot be attacked or compromised by anyone -- even colluding state-level actors
它能承受任何人攻击或破坏---甚至串通州级的议员
and giant multi-national corporations... despotic, disgusting, dictatorial regimes
和大型跨国公司... 专制， 恶心，独裁的政权
and other censorship ridden hell holes...
以及其他检查制度...也不能动摇它
The only applications you need that for can be counted on the fingers of one hand.
您唯一需要的应用程序可以用一只手就可以数过来
But I'll tell you which application immediately is important: money.
但我会告诉你哪个应用程序是最重要的：货币
We don't like to think that money is an important application, especially in western liberal culture.
我们不愿意承认货币是重要的应用， 尤其是在西方自由文化中。
Here, money is dirty and "the root of all evil."
在这里，金钱是肮脏的，是“万恶之源”
It's not the money that's dirty, it's the current architecture of money.
黑钱不是钱，这就是当前的货币体系
Centralised, hierarchical, controlled.
集中，分层，受控
That is dirty.
真是肮脏
[We have turned] money into a network protocol that we can spread to the entire world.
[我们已经]把货币变成了网络协议 我们可以传播到整个世界
[We can] give it to every person who currently doesn't have access to banking facilities,
[我们可以]给每一个目前无法使用银行设施的人
to billions of people who are cut off from the financial system just to give us a bourgeois sense of safety
当前数以亿计的人在金融世界中被隔绝， 只是为了给我们资产阶级安全感
-- which is a lie.
-这是一个谎言
[The financial system] is a system of control so pervasive that it has been weaponised throughout
[金融系统]是一种控制系统， 这种情况是如此普遍，以至于它在整个过程中都被武器化了
the West, to be used as a system of political power and control.
西方，用金融系统获取政治权力和控制权
Proprietary money is the cancer of modern societies.
专有货币是现代社会的癌症
It has infected democracy. It is killing democracy.
它感染了民主。它正在杀死民主
The answer to that is open, neutral, borderless, censorship-resistant, open-source money
这个问题的答案就是开放，中立，无国界，不受审查的开源货币
as a network protocol. As an open interface.
把它作为网络协议。 作为一个开放的界面
As a system that can be [used by] anyone who has an IP connected device of the most basic
作为一个可以被具有最基本的网络连接设备人都可以使用的软件
functionality, which gives them the power to independently verify, authorise, authenticate,
赋予他们独立验证，授权，认证的力量
transact globally with anyone.
与任何人进行全球交易的力量
Once we have that solid platform, we can build applications of trust like authenticated voting,
一旦有了这个坚实的平台，我们就可以构建 信任的应用，例如经过验证的投票，
ownership of real-estate, and other assets.
房地产所有权和其他资产
Applications like open-source law through smart contracts.
通过智能合约来开源法律等应用
Realise that cryptocurrencies today are the largest open, public, consumer / civilian deployment
认识到今天的加密货币是最大的公开，公共，消费者/民用部署
of public key cryptography that has ever happened (besides SSL).
已经发生的公钥密码学（除了SSL）
We have now arrived at the golden age of cryptography.
现在，我们进入了密码技术的黄金时代
The cypherpunks are finally winning.
密码朋克最终会胜利
We can apply that amazing technology to one of humanity's most ancient and fundamental technologies:
我们可以将惊人的技术应用于人类最古老和最基本的技术：
a system for the communication of value, that we call money.
价值传达系统 -- 我们称之为货币
For the first time in history, money is a content-type, a protocol.
有史以来第一次， 货币是一种信息类型，一种协议
Thank you. [Applause]
谢谢。 [掌声]